if you don't already know trap bars are
a great alternative to a traditional
barbell when it comes to your
deadlifting that's because they're
specifically designed to align the
weight you're lifting with your center
of gravity as opposed to holding a
barbell out in front of you so if you're
looking for a new specialty bar for your
home gym you might want to consider the
rep Fitness open trap bar the open
design right here is going to make it
easier for you to do loaded carries or
Farmers walks you know whatever you want
to call them but it also opens up the
possibility to do some alternating
lunges as well and plus this is a
rackable trap bar so it's going to be
compatible with your power Rack or your
squat rack especially if you have a rep
Fitness one that way you can do some
squats maybe even some bench presses
with it if you want to the built-in Jack
makes it super easy for you to load and
unload your weighted plates plus it acts
as a counterweight so the bar stays
balanced at all times I hope y'all are
ready because I got a lot to talk about
today so let's get to it
thank you
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video I've got the rep Fitness open trap
bar info review if you don't know how
this works in this video today I'm going
to tell you guys everything you need to
know about this piece of equipment from
the price and the features as well as
some pros and cons and of course who
should or maybe should not add this to
their home gym now let's pump the brakes
before I get going with all of that I
gotta let you know we've reviewed a ton
of trivars on barbin.com and we also
made a best list so if you want to
browse our top picks all you got to do
is search bar Bend best trap bars our
list is going to pull right up for you
you can find out for yourself which one
cracks that number one spot
let's talk about what I like about the
rep Fitness open trap bar and I got to
kick this off by stating the obvious
I love the open design it makes it so
much easier to get in and out of the bar
you know you don't have you know a bar
back here to step up and over like you
do with a traditional hex trap bar and
that's just really nice and especially
because it's also going to allow you to
do additional exercises as I was talking
about you know specifically those
alternating lunges that's just really
nice you also have this built-in Jack
right here and that's just crucial in my
opinion you know it's how I have it set
up right now and it's going to make
things so much easier on you when you go
to load and unload your weight plates
now let's talk about these handles for a
second they're 28 millimeters diameter
which is really nice you know it's
pretty much identical to a barbell
they're also fully knurled and I really
love this knurling pattern right here
seems to be a volcano pattern and that's
really going to give you the best grip
possible real quick if you don't know
what volcano knurling is so every single
point right here the knurling it dips in
like a volcano so you have four points
of contact on your hand it's going to
give you pretty much the best grip you
could ask for all right anyways so
that's just really nice you know it
gives you a really good grip you also
have four different options in terms of
the handles so we have the standard ones
there's a wide pair a narrow pair and
rotating handles so it's nice you just
kind of have some variety and you can
get you know some that are going to suit
your needs the best so obviously you
have two handles on each side the top
one sits 11 inches off the ground which
is going to be great for anybody who's
learning the proper deadlifting
technique or maybe you have a little bit
of a ailment injury you're dealing with
that's nice and over time if you want to
you know increase your range of motion
you can grab all of these bottom ones
they're eight inches off the ground so
you know that just kind of helps you out
a little bit which is cool the loading
sleeves are 16 and a half inches long
and
that's a bit of a rarity when it comes
to a travel you know most of them are
shorter and that kind of limits the
amount of weight you can load onto one
of these bad boys and speaking of
loadable weight this trap bar can handle
up to 1300 pounds I think it's 1 350 you
know to be right on the nose with it so
that's really nice too you know so if
you're an elite lifter that's you know
gonna be a really nice thing for you
right there and last thing here you know
this is a rackable trap bar so as I
mentioned earlier you know it's gonna be
compatible with your power Rack or squat
rack you know especially a rep Fitness
one and that's really nice you know you
can do some squats with this if you want
to bench pressing might feel a little
bit awkward at first because you know
you're kind of having to do a different
type of lift than you normally would
with you know a barbell but you
definitely can squat with it and there's
also a little bit of knurling right here
on this tubing and you know it's not
abrasive by any means but it does give
you a little bit of texture that way the
bar can sit on your upper back and it's
not really going to go anywhere so
that's just really cool too
all right now when it comes to those
potential cons you might run into I
really haven't been able to come up with
very many let's talk about the money
though this trap bar is going to run you
around 400 bucks and you're definitely
paying for the Innovative design right
here and it's pretty much one of a kind
but at the same time you can get a
traditional hex trap bar for about half
the price and then also I personally
love the knurling on these handles but
might be a little bit too sharp for some
people you know texture is all personal
preference so that's just another thing
right there too you know you might not
be too crazy about it
foreign
so let's talk about some money and once
again the rep Fitness open trap bar is
going to run you right around 400 bucks
but if you go for those rotating handles
it's going to run you around 470 dollars
I also want to mention you do have the
option of adding on multiple handles
when you're going to do your purchase so
those rotating handles are going to run
you around 170 bucks while the wide
narrow and standard ones are going to
run you around 90 so you know 470 bucks
for one piece of equipment is kind of a
lot of money and especially with a
specialty bar you know yes this one is
you know pretty versatile it's more
versatile than a standard hex trap bar
with those standard hex trap bars are
also about half the price now when you
do compare this one to other open trap
Boards out there it's it's a little bit
cheaper than some of those other options
so if you're dead set on getting an open
trap bar for your home gym this might be
you know one of the best options
regarding the price but you know when
we're talking about versatility you know
what's more versatile than a trap bar a
barbell which is also going to run you
around you know the same amount of money
so definitely just keep all that in mind
as you go to make your purchase
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with the rep
Fitness open trap bar so this bar is 84
inches long and it weighs right around
58 pounds plus these Chrome loading
sleeves are 16.5 inches long now let's
talk about the handles really quick the
28 millimeters in diameter which is
really nice you know it's going to fill
up your palms you're going to get a nice
grip but also fully knurled which I just
am ranting and raving about I love it
the height of these handles are not
going to change depending on you know
which ones you go with so the top one's
11 inches off the ground or the bottom
one is eight inches it's nice how you
can kind of increase that range of
motion over time or maybe you don't want
to that's just nice now the width is
going to in fact vary you know depending
on which handles you decide to go with
so the narrow handles will be 23 inches
apart the standard ones that we have are
25 inches apart those wide ones are 27
inches apart and the rotating ones are a
little over 26 I think it's 26.4 inches
apart so definitely keep that in mind
mind you know that way you're able to
really figure out which one suits you
the best and then obviously we've got to
talk about the built-in Jacks probably
my favorite feature at the end of the
day it just makes it so much easier to
you know a get in and out of the trap
bar but also you know it's gonna make it
so much easier for you to load and
unload your weighted plates because you
know sitting up nice and tall like this
those plates are not going to touch the
ground at all just makes life so much
easier
all right y'all I want to give you a
quick demo and a nice up close and
personal look at all the fine features
with this trap bar let's talk about you
know the framework right here you know
once again this steel frame is powder
coated you know it's going to add to
some rust protection and probably even
some you know chip resistant if it
clanks in anything you know whatever
anyways so let's talk about this
knurling right here you got a little bit
of a knurling pattern really only going
to come in handy whenever you you know
go to do a back squat and keep this bar
up on your upper back but it might also
help a little bit you know just to grab
and kind of move it from A to B within
your home gym which is really nice now
speaking of knurling I want to talk
about these handles once again you know
I just cannot get enough of it to me
personally it's kind of like Goldilocks
and the Three Bears you know not too
abrasive you know not too passive or
just right in my opinion and that's
obviously a really good thing especially
you know as you're going to lift some
heavy weight you never want to be
limited by your grip so that's really
good so
you have two different heights obviously
you know this top one right here is
going to be 11 inches off the ground
whenever you throw weight plates on this
bottom one is going to be eight inches
off the ground you know whenever you
flip it because you can do it both ways
right here now regardless of your
handles you go for wide narrow rotating
standard like we have they're all going
to have you know 28 millimeter Handles
in diameter and the height is going to
be the same of all of them but that
width obviously is is going to change
you know all across the board now this
built-in Jack is amazing nothing short
of amazing makes life so much easier on
you as you're going to load and unload
your plates and even just storage too
it's the best way for it to be stored so
that's really nice too you know it just
sits nice and sturdy right here I mean
it's really not it's not going to fall
over on its own which is nice now
extra 16.5 inch chrome loading sleeves
right here big fan of that too because
you know you're going to be able to load
more weight on this trap bar than a lot
of other options that are out there now
let's go ahead and throw some weight on
there while I'm talking about it
and as you can see you know it just
makes it so much easier because you
don't have to worry about the plate you
know getting stuck on the ground or
whatever but one thing
this tribor did not come with any weight
collars so definitely get your own
and toss them on there for your own
protection you definitely don't want
that to slide off on you
all right and then so this is really
where it's it's cool you know we're 11
inches off the ground right here excuse
me eight inches off the ground right
here but this one and then if we flip it
that's when you're 11 inches off the
ground as you can see so that's really
nice you know you can just get up in
position
get ready to go do your deadlifts
now I want to talk about how this is a
rackable trap bar really unique not
every trap bar out there is like that so
just hang tight one second
all right so just grab this bad boy
right here
Bring It On Up
that's what this is for right here this
little section
it's going to fit on those J Hooks just
really really nice right there so you
can bench press with this strap bar I
found it to be a little bit awkward so
it might not be you know the best thing
to do
you definitely could squat with it
though so I like putting my hands out
here and that's remember you got that
knurling right there it's going to sit
right there on your upper back
just walk on out and you're good to go
so you know there's just so much
that you can do with this trap bar so
much so that I'm starting to run out of
breath right now
and that's really what just would make
it such a solid addition to your home
gym okay so who should purchase the rep
Fitness open trap bar well for starters
if you're new to dead lifting and you're
wanting to learn the proper technique
which you definitely should you don't
want to get hurt this is going to be
really nice for you know especially with
these elevated handles and over time you
know you can increase your range of
motion so that's really nice this is
also a really versatile products of
Versatility is your main factor I think
you're really going to like the open
design here you know it's going to allow
you so like I said it's rackable also so
you can do squats with it you can do
alternating lunges with it you can prop
your foot up on your weight bench and
you can do some Bulgarian split squats
and there's a lot you can do here and
once again once you compare the price of
this trap bar to the other open trap
bars that are on the market this one's
actually a little bit cheaper which is
another good thing going for it
all right now what about those people
who might not want to purchase this trap
bar let's talk about money first if
you're on a tight budget you know you
might not want to spend 400 maybe even
close to 500 to 470 for those rotating
handles on one piece of equipment so
definitely keep that in mind we gotta
talk about available space too so if
you're tight on Space you know 84 inches
in length this might not be the best
option for you and you can make the
argument you know about storing it
vertically but since you have to
assemble these sleeves and they're not
welded together you run that risk of
wear and tear at an accelerated rate by
storing it vertically and kind of having
that pressure really where it shouldn't
be and then lastly we gotta talk about
versatility yes in regards to trap bars
this is about as versatile as it gets
but you know what's more versatile a
barbell and that's either going to be
around the same amount of money or it
might even save you money so definitely
keep that in mind
foreign
that's all I have for you guys today on
the rep Fitness open trap bar there's a
lot I like about this bad boy you know
specifically the open design with that
built-in Jack it makes it so easy for me
to load and unload my plates these fully
knurled handles give me a sticky tack
grip when I'm working out and I really
like the elevated handle as well you
know it adds some variety and allows me
to you know decrease my range of motion
if I want to also you know these 16 and
a half inch loading sleeves just really
get the job done for me it's basically
identical to a traditional barbell and
that's just something that I just
personally love just remember you know
this is a little bit pricey so it might
not be the best for everybody thanks for
watching y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
tell you everything you need to know
about this trap bar as always keep your
eyes peeled for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com because we
have a full written review ready for you
to read it all you got to do is type in
barbend rep Fitness open trap bar review
it'll pull right up and you be able to
go over everything we discussed here
today you might even learn something new
I'll catch y'all next time
foreign